■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  Silmar
翻译  送小孩
翻译  小熊嘟嘟
翻译  尼克白
翻译  树树
翻译  泰斯
校对  泰斯·雪诺
校对  Silmar
时间轴  崽猪
时间轴  imok
时间轴  sweet宝宝88
时间轴  Sage~Zweig
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
特效/后期  鱼骨头
特效/后期  拉图
总监  泰斯·雪诺
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第八集
到了
Here we are.
好了吗
Ready?
《卡斯特梅的雨季》
"The Rains of Castamere."
你他妈聋的吗
You fucking deaf?
每次都猜错还错得一样
Same wrong guess every fucking time.
听仔细了  蠢货
Listen, you cunt.
《狗熊和美少女》
"The Bear and the Maiden Fair."
终于有个长耳朵的男人了
There's a man with an ear.
可惜你的鸡鸡小得像根刺儿
Too bad you got a hangnail for a cock.
头一次见你脱裤子的时候
First time I saw you with your breeches down,
还以为你是个太监呢
I thought you were a eunuch.
你们见过的  姑娘们
You've seen it, girls.
像只探头缩脑的小蜗牛
Like a baby snail peeking out of his shell.
今天早上你孩子哭闹
Your baby was crying this morning.
吵醒我了
Woke me up.
你听到没有
You hear me?
听到了
Yes.
你有什么要说的吗
Well, got anything to say?
抱歉他吵醒你了
I'm sorry he woke you up.
我才不管你抱歉不抱歉
I don't care if you're sorry.
让那孩子安静点儿
Keep that baby quiet
否则我自己动手
or I will.
不许你碰他
Don't you ever touch him.
野人小婊子
Little wildling bitch.
你该跟你的同类在一起
You should have stayed with your own kind.
听见没有
You listening to me?
-闭上你的嘴  -什么
- Shut your mouth. - What?
不过是只猫头鹰  你这蠢婊子
It's just an owl, you dumb bitch.
不  不是
No, it's not.
我不该把她留在那儿
I should never have left her there.
-你也不能未卜先知  -我当然应该知道
- You couldn't have known. - Of course I could've known.
他们一直在袭击周围的村庄
They've been raiding the villages close by.
兄弟们被杀害  我们却缩在这里
And we just cower in here while they slaughter our brothers.
我们的兄弟奉命守在黑城堡
Our brothers had orders to stay at Castle Black.
那就无所谓咯
So it's all right, then?
黑杰克  木桶和穆利被砍成碎片
Black Jack and Kegs and Mully chopped to pieces
是因为他们违纪在先
'cause they broke the rules?
我没说无所谓
I didn't say it was all right.
我说的是他们不该在那里
I'm saying they shouldn't have been there.
我们誓言守护王国
We're pledged to guard the realms of men.
她是因为我才死的
She's dead because of me.
我们连鼹鼠村都守护不了
We can't even guard Mole's Town.
我们不能追击  你也清楚
We can't go after them. You know that.
那样正中他们下怀
It's what they want.
小山姆
And little Sam.
简直是我亲手杀了他们
As if I cut their throats myself.
或许她躲起来了呢
Maybe she managed to hide herself.
之前我还以为你们全死了
I thought all of you was dead.
你们随莫尔蒙北上  一个都没回来
You went north with Mormont and no one came back.
过了那么久
Not for ages.
可是你们回来了
But then you did.
她打卡斯特身边活过来的
She survived Craster
那可是我见过的最操蛋的家伙
and he was the worst shit I've ever met.
一路走回长城  她也挺过来了
She survived the long march to the Wall.
她还躲过一只异鬼  操他娘的
She survived a white walker, for fuck's sake.
她或许逃过此劫了
She might have got out.
或许吧
She might have.
既然他们袭击鼹鼠村
If they hit Mole's Town,
下一步就是这里
then we're next.
曼斯的大军一定很近了
Mance and his army must be close.
他们有十万人
100,000 of them.
我们还剩多少人  一百零五
And there's what, 105 of us left?
你算上黑杰克  木桶和穆利了吧
You counting Black Jack, Kegs, and Mully?
一百零二
102.
一百零二人怎么抵挡十万大军
How do 102 men stop 100,000?
甭管谁死在最后  发发慈悲
Whoever dies last, be a good lad
把我们全烧了
and burn the rest of us.
好容易混个一了百了
Once I'm done with this world,
我可不想再回来
I don't want to come back.
你说他在监视你
You think he was spying on you?
不  不是监视
No, not spying.
多斯拉克人认为外族人羞于裸露实在荒谬可笑
The Dothraki think outsiders are ridiculous taking shame in the naked body.
他们在星空下做爱  让整个卡拉萨见证
They make love under the stars for the whole khalasar to see.
是的  陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
可你不是多斯拉克人
But you are not Dothraki.
不是
No.
我觉得这没什么大不了
Well, I don't see why it matters.
灰虫子又没兴趣
Grey Worm isn't interested.
无垢者并不喜欢我们掩盖在衣裙底下的身体
None of the Unsullied care what's under our clothes.
他有兴趣
He was interested.
什么
What?
我想他是有兴趣的
I believe he was interested.
善主们阉割男孩
When the slavers castrate the boys,
是全部割掉吗
do they take all of it?
全部
All of it?
就是
The--
鸡和蛋啊
the pillar and the stones.
我不知道  陛下
I don't know, Your Grace.
你就没想过吗
Haven't you ever wondered?
想过  陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
弥桑黛
Missandei.
我来道歉
你无需道歉
希望我没有吓到你
没有
你教我学习通用语
The lessons you give I in common tongue...
这对自己很珍贵
these are precious to I.
-对我  -对我
- To me. - To me.
我不记得教过你"珍贵"这个词
I don't remember teaching you the word precious.
安达尔人乔拉  他教给自己...
Jorah the Andal, he teaches I--
他教给我这个词
he teaches me this word.
你还记得出生时的名字吗
Do you remember the name you were given at birth?
我什么都不记得
I remember nothing.
只有无垢者
Only Unsullied.
他们阉割你的时候
When they cut you,
你记得吗
do you remember that?
对不起
I'm sorry.
他们那样对你  我很抱歉
I'm sorry they did that to you.
为什么  为什么抱歉
Why? Why sorry?
因为那样对一个男孩  是很可怕的事
It's a terrible thing to do to a boy.
如果善主们没有阉割我
If the masters never cut me,
我就不会是无垢者
I never am Unsullied.
风暴降生丹妮莉丝下令杀死善主那天
I never stand in the Plaza of Pride
我也不会站在骄傲广场
when Daenerys Stormborn orders us to kill the masters.
我不会被选出来领导无垢者
I never am chosen to lead the Unsullied.
也见不到纳斯岛的弥桑黛
I never meet Missandei from the island of Naath.
对不起
I am sorry I--
今天的事
for today.
对不起
I am sorry.
灰虫子
我很高兴你看到了我
我也是
海怪
Kraken.
待在海里才是王者
Strong as long as they're in the sea.
一旦离开水
When you take them out of the water,
没有骨头
no bones.
就会被自己的体重压垮
They collapse under their proud weight
变成一摊没用的烂泥
and slump into a heap of nothing.
你以为他们有自知之明
You'd think they know that.
太不幸啦  他们脑子不好使
Unfortunately, they're not very bright.
你该对他们说什么
What do you tell them?
我是席恩·葛雷乔伊
I'm Theon Greyjoy,
巴隆之子  铁群岛的继承人
son of Balon, heir to the Iron Islands.
-其实你是什么呢  -我是臭佬
- And what are you really? - I'm Reek.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你看起来像个货真价实的大人
You do look very much like a lord.
威严又尊贵
Formidable, proud.
我是臭佬
I'm Reek.
直到何时
Until when?
直到永远
Always.
-永生永世  -没错
- Forever. - That's right.
直到你在泥土中腐烂
Until you're rotting in the ground.
要记得你是什么  不是什么
Remember what you are and what you're not.
给我拿下卡林湾
Bring me Moat Cailin.
站住
No closer.
来者何人
Who are you?
我是肯宁
I'm Kenning,
驻军指挥官
commander of this garrison.
-你说你是席恩·葛雷乔伊  -是的
- And you say you're Theon Greyjoy? - Yes.
我凭什么相信你
And why should I believe that?
我生于派克岛  父亲是巴隆·葛雷乔伊
I was born on Pyke to Balon Greyjoy.
我是他的三子  也是唯一幸存的儿子
His third and last living son.
我是你们的王子
I am your prince.
我向淹神发誓
I swear it by the Drowned God.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
如果你是我的王子
And if you were my prince,
为何与波顿军为伍
why are you marching with a Bolton army?
波顿大人在临冬城俘虏了我
Lord Bolton took me captive after Winterfell.
因你我同是铁种  他派我来诚心讲和
He sent me to treat with you in good faith as your fellow ironborn.
波顿大人想要什么
And what does Lord Bolton want?
你们受伤病折磨
You are fading from sickness,
寡不敌众
you are badly outnumbered,
而且你们距离大海数百哩之遥
and you're hundreds of miles from the sea.
波顿大人恳请你为手下着想
Lord Bolton implores you to protect your men
放弃这座久守不利的要塞
and abandon this fortress you can no longer hold.
若这样做  他必将以礼相待
Do this, and he will be just and fair with you
正如他待我一样
as he has been with me.
波顿家族答应放你们平安返回磐石海岸
The Boltons will give you safe passage to the Stony Shore.
他要让我们投降吗
He wants us to surrender?
我的父亲  你的国王
My own father, your king,
许多年前曾向劳勃·拜拉席恩投降
surrendered years ago to Robert Baratheon.
我亲眼见他屈膝下跪
I watched him bend the knee.
投降并不可耻
There was no shame there.
他英勇战斗过  你也一样
He fought with honor, as did you.
"不可耻"  "英勇战斗过"
"No shame." "Fought with honor."
抱歉  我没听清
I'm sorry, I didn't hear.
"不可耻"  "英勇战斗过"
"No shame." "Fought with honor."
只有听话的狗儿才讲得出这种话
Only a whipped dog would speak this way.
或者是娘们
Or a woman.
你是娘们吗  小子
Are you a woman, boy?
你不知道...
You don't know--
铁种不会投降
The ironborn will not surrender.
臭佬  我叫臭佬
Reek. My name is Reek...
把这话带给你主子
You go tell your master that,
席恩·葛雷乔伊  管你他妈的是谁
Theon Greyjoy, or whoever the fuck you are.
我叫臭佬
My name is Reek.
你嘀嘀咕咕地念叨什么
What in the hell are you muttering?
我是臭佬
I'm Reek.
臭佬
Reek.
投降就能活命吗
If we yield, we live?
纸上是这样写的吗
Is that what it says on this paper here?
是的  叫人升起白旗  打开城门
Yes. Have your men raise the white flag and open the gates.
你们就要回家了
You're going home.
你不会真以为我会放他们走吧
You didn't really think I'd let them go, did you?
现在不流行剥皮了
It's fallen out of fashion, flaying.
很可惜  却是事实
Sad, but true.
传统很重要
Traditions are important.
没有历史  我们容身何地
Where are we without our history?
-对吗  -对  大人
- Eh? - Yes, my lord.
我们能回家了吗
Will we go home now?
我们可以回了
I believe we will.
回我们的新家
To our new home.
你有外邦血统  对吗  贝里席
You have foreign blood, don't you, Baelish?
我的曾祖父来自布拉佛斯  是的
A great-grandfather from Braavos, yes.
追根溯源  恐怕所有人的祖先都是外邦人
I suppose all of our ancestors came from somewhere else originally.
我们的祖先几千年前就在艾林谷定居
Our forebearers settled the Vale thousands of years ago.
从那时起  我们便拒外敌于门外
We've fought off invaders ever since.
艾林谷的绝境之美
The beauty of the Vale is matched only
与各大家族们的高贵气质相得益彰
by the nobility of its great families.
艾林夫人常对我说
Lady Arryn often told me
您是她的岩石  罗伊斯大人
that you were her rock, lord Royce.
她从没对我提过你  贝里席
She told me nothing about you, Baelish.
但不用她说  我也对你有所耳闻
But I didn't need to hear from her.
放债者  皮条客
Moneylender. Whoremonger.
你舔了泰温·兰尼斯特的靴子这么久
You've been licking Tywin Lannister's boots so long,
-舌头竟然没有变黑  -大人
- it's a wonder your tongue's not black. - My lord--
当琼恩·艾林任命你为财政大臣时
And when Jon Arryn named you Master of Coin,
没人在乎
no one cared.
那差事向来脏手  给脏人去做又有何妨
Always been a grubby job. Why not let a grubby man do it?
可当我听说你潜入谷地
But when I heard you were lurking here,
讨好起艾林夫人...
fawning over the Lady Arryn--
是艾林夫人邀请我来的
Lady Arryn invited me.
我们从小就很亲近
She and I have been close since childhood.
是的  我们都知道你们有多亲
Yes, we all know how close you were.
艾林夫人的嗜好是她的私事
Lady Arryn's predilections were her own affair.
她的死是公事
Her death is our affair.
当然了  她自杀而死  令我们伤碎了心
Of course. Her suicide shattered us all.
她的脾气确实古怪  人人皆知
She was an odd fish. Everyone knew that.
可是自杀  她很爱那个儿子
But suicide? She adored that boy of hers.
我觉得她不会抛弃儿子  至少不是自愿的
I don't see her abandoning him. Not by choice.
真奇怪  你才来几天
Strange that within days of your arrival,
就与艾林夫人结婚  而她跌下了月门
you've married Lady Arryn and she's fallen through the Moon Door.
她在世时总是很忧郁
She was always prone to melancholy.
我夫人与这个残酷的世界格格不入
My lady wasn't meant for a world as brutal as ours.
我们听说有个目击者  是个女孩
We were told there was a witness. A girl.
是你的外甥女  对吧
A niece of yours, I believe.
她是个无知愚昧的女孩
A girl with no learning and scattered wits.
我敢保证  她帮不上什么忙
I assure you, she would be of no help.
我们想找她谈谈
We'd like to speak with her.
-我去找她  -不必了
- Let me fetch her. - No need.
我们想听到未经篡改的证词
We prefer to hear her testimony unadulterated.
过来  孩子
Come closer, child.
不用怕我们  也不用怕他
You have nothing to fear from us or him.
这位贝里席大人可是你舅舅
Lord Baelish here is your uncle?
你名叫阿莲
Your name is Alayne?
若是贝里席大人不在这里
Perhaps you would feel more comfortable
你是不是自在些
if Lord Baelish left the room.
-夫人...  -我没问你
- My lady-- - I wasn't asking you.
-他可以留下  -姑娘说吧  你有眼有嘴
- He can stay. - Speak up, girl, you're not a damn kitchen mouse.
看见什么照实说
Tell us what you saw.
对不起  贝里席大人
I'm sorry, Lord Baelish.
我必须说实话
I have to tell the truth.
我全都说
I'll tell you everything.
说吧  阿莲  全都说出来
Please, Alayne, leave nothing out.
我不叫阿莲
My name is not Alayne.
我是珊莎·史塔克
It's Sansa Stark,
艾德·史塔克公爵的长女
eldest daughter of Lord Eddard Stark.
罗伊斯大人  您作客临冬城时我们谋过面
Lord Royce, we met when you came to Winterfell.
当日您护送您儿子威玛爵士赴长城就任
You were escorting your son Ser Waymar to the Wall.
珊莎·史塔克
Sansa Stark?
你这小人渣  敢当我面谎话连篇
You tell lies right to my face, you little worm?
贝里席大人说过很多谎话
Lord Baelish has told many lies.
但都是为了保护我
All to protect me.
父亲被害之后
Since my father was executed,
我便被当作人质困在君临
I have been a hostage in King's Landing.
成了玩物  供乔佛里折磨  任瑟曦作弄
A plaything for Joffrey to torture or Queen Cersei to torment.
他们打我  侮辱我
They beat me, they humiliated me,
还逼我嫁给小恶魔
they married me to the Imp.
我在君临无亲无故
I had no friends in King's Landing...
只有他
except one.
他救了我
He saved me.
趁乱带我出城
Smuggled me away when he had the chance.
他知道我在鹰巢城
He knew I'd be safe here in the Eyrie
有亲姨妈莱莎庇护  可以安身
with my own blood, my Aunt Lysa.
兰尼斯特党羽遍天下
The Lannisters have friends everywhere.
连谷地也不例外
Even the Vale.
他要我发誓不道出真名
He made me swear not to tell anyone my true name.
小姐  我们会替你保守秘密
Your secret is safe with us, my lady.
你父亲就在这堡中长大
Your father grew up right here in these halls.
我们很多次一起狩猎
We hunted together many times.
他是个好人
He was a fine man.
珊莎  你姨妈到底是什么回事
Tell us what happened to your aunt, Sansa.
大人  夫人  诸位深知我姨妈为人
You knew her well, my lords, my lady.
必然知道她内心纷扰已久
You knew she was a troubled woman.
她一直爱慕贝里席大人
She always loved Lord Baelish.
她亲口跟我说过
She told me herself.
贝里席八岁那年身背布袋  带着全部家当
From the moment he arrived at the gates of Riverrun,
初到奔流城那日  姨妈便爱上了他
a boy of eight carrying everything he owned in a little sack.
她向我坦承  她从未爱过艾林公爵
She confessed to me she never loved Lord Arryn.
只是逃不过众多女人的命运  从父命嫁给他
She did as her father commanded, as so many of us have.
等到终于有机会与贝里席大人厮守终身时
When the gods finally allowed her to be with Lord Baelish,
她是那么高兴
she was so happy.
可转瞬即逝
For a time.
姨妈本性善妒
My aunt was a jealous lady.
她担心贝里席大人不再爱她
She was terrified that Lord Baelish didn't love her anymore.
恋上年轻姑娘  弃她而去
That he would abandon her for a younger woman.
然后
And then...
有一天她看见贝里席大人亲我
one day she saw him kiss me.
珊莎小姐
Lady Sansa.
只是亲了下脸颊  仅此而已  罗伊斯大人
It was a peck on the cheek, Lord Royce, nothing more.
贝里席大人现在是我姻亲的姨夫
Lord Baelish is my uncle now, in truth, by marriage.
他一直对我照顾有加
He's always been so kind to me.
我喜欢这里  喜欢自由自在
I was so happy to be here, to be free.
这一切都是因为他
All because of him.
但姨妈容不下我
But my aunt turned on me.
她诅咒我  骂我荡妇
She cursed me. Called me a whore.
还威胁要把我从月门推下去
Promised to throw me through the Moon Door.
贝里席大人试图安抚她
When Lord Baelish tried to calm her,
她便出手打他
she struck him.
她说她生无可恋
She said she didn't want to live anymore.
于是站到月门边沿
She stood on the edge of that Moon Door.
贝里席本想劝服她
He tried to reason with her.
还保证今生只爱她一人
Promised her she was the only one he had ever loved,
但她还是踏出月门  她...
but she stepped through those doors and she was--
好姑娘  这不是你的错
Shh, it's not your fault, sweet girl.
不是你的错
It's not your fault.
你也看到她教子无方
You could see it in the way she raised that boy.
十岁的孩子还在啃奶头
Feeding him from her own teats when he was 10 years old.
罗伊斯大人  现在哪是说这事的时候
Lord Royce! This is hardly the time.
抱歉  夫人
Apologies, my lady.
还有贝里席
And to you as well, Baelish.
先前对你多有责难
We treated you a bit harshly.
罗伊斯大人  您是在秉公执法
You want justice, Lord Royce.
我不敢有怨言
I can hardly complain about that.
我求的也是个公正
I want the same.
自杀这事哪里谈得上公正不公正
Not much justice to be meted out in suicide, is there?
对莱莎谈不上  对她儿子可不尽然
For Lysa, no. But for her son?
二十年前  谷地骑士追随琼恩·艾林
Only 20 years ago, the knights of the Vale
奈德·史塔克和劳勃·拜拉席恩出谷
rode behind Jon Arryn, Ned Stark, Robert Baratheon.
起兵对抗疯王
They fought together to overcome the Mad King.
从那以后  艾林  罗伊斯
And since then, Arryn and Royce,
科布瑞  韦伍德
Corbray, Waynwood,
谷地各大家族偏安一隅  隔岸观火
all the great houses of the Vale watched from the corner.
像是胆小怕事的孩子在酒馆看人打架
A timid boy at a tavern brawl.
你这是责怪我等贪生怕死吗
Are you questioning our courage?
我只想知道你们到底支持谁
I want to know which side you're on.
是杀你故友奈德·史塔克的
Do you support the Lannisters,
兰尼斯特家族吗
the house that executed your friend Ned Stark?
我们当然不是兰尼斯特那边的
Of course we don't support the damn Lannisters.
不是  凯特琳·史塔克求助莱莎却遭拒绝
No? Catelyn Stark begged her sister for support and Lysa refused.
你们明哲保身  却让泰温·兰尼斯特
By staying out of the fray, you've allowed Tywin Lannister
得以趁机各个击破
to destroy his rivals on every compass point.
事到如今谁还能与他为敌
Who stands against him now?
贝里席大人  那你想让我们拥护谁
Who would you have us back, Lord Baelish?
罗柏·史塔克已死
Robb Stark is dead.
我要你们拥护罗宾·艾林
I'd have you back Robin Arryn,
谷地主君
Lord of the Vale.
他只是个羸弱的小孩子
Robin Arryn is a sickly little boy.
再羸弱也可以长大成人
And sickly little boys sometimes become powerful men.
幼年早夭可是常事
More often they die young.
我虽钟情于莱莎
I adored Lysa with all my heart.
可她护子心切  溺爱过头
But she loved her son so much, she became overprotective.
他要学习如何使剑
He needs to learn how to swing a sword.
如何骑马
How to ride a horse.
-没错  是时候了  -正是时候
- Aye, it's time. - Yes, it's time.
让他游历谷地
Time for him to tour the Vale,
巡视治下的各家城堡
to visit all the castles in his domain.
罗宾离巢的时候到了
Time for Robin to leave the nest.
巴利斯坦爵士
Ser Barristan.
何事
Yes?
谁派你来的
Who sent you?
弥林
渊凯
雅洛斯岛
狭海
君临
-巴利斯坦爵士  -乔拉爵士
- Ser Barristan. - Ser Jorah.
是我忘了去开会吗
Have I forgotten a council meeting?
不是
No.
这是什么
What's this?
赦免书
A royal pardon
劳勃·拜拉席恩签署的
signed by Robert Baratheon.
你是来监视她的
You spied on her.
这是谁给你的
Who gave you this?
重要吗
Does it matter?
你告诉她了吗
Have you told her?
我要先与你对峙  光明正大
I wanted to tell you first, man-to-man
而不是背着你告密
rather than go behind your back.
让我找她单独谈谈
Let me speak with her in private.
你永远别想单独见她了
You'll never be alone with her again.
篡夺者为什么赦免你
Why did the usurper pardon you?
我们最好能单独谈谈
If we could speak alone.
不行  就在这里说
No, speak to me here.
给我个说法
Explain it to me.
您认为这信是谁送到弥林来的
Who do you think sent this to Meereen?
谁从中得利
Who profits?
这是泰温·兰尼斯特的诡计
This is the work of Tywin Lannister.
他想离间我们
He wants to divide us.
如果我们勾心斗角  他便可高忱无忧
If we're fighting each other, we're not fighting him.
赦免书是我们相见那年签署的
The pardon was signed the year we met.
你为什么得到赦免
Why were you pardoned?
别告诉我这份文书是伪造的
Unless you're saying this document was forged.
并非伪造
It is not forged.
那为什么呢
Why, then?
我写了几封信给瓦里斯
I sent letters to Varys,
君临的那个情报总管
the spymaster of King's Landing.
信里写了些什么
What was the content of these letters?
-情报  -什么情报
- Information. - What information?
您和韦赛里斯到达潘托斯的日期
When you and Viserys arrived in Pentos.
他把您嫁给卓戈卡奥的计划
His plan to marry you to Khal Drogo.
你们的结婚日期
When you were married.
您哥哥的死期
When your brother died.
你告诉他我怀了卓戈的骨肉
You told him I was carrying Drogo's child?
-我...  -"是"或"不是"
- I-- - Yes or no?
-卡丽熙  -别再这么叫我
- Khaleesi. - Don't call me that.
你是不是告诉他我怀了卓戈的骨肉
Did you tell him I was carrying Drogo's child?
是
Yes.
正是因为你给出的情报
That wine merchant tried to poison me
那个酒贩子才来毒害我
because of your information.
我为您挡下了那杯酒
I stopped you from drinking his wine.
因为你知道酒里下了毒
Because you knew it was poisoned.
我只是怀疑
I suspected.
你从一开始
You betrayed me
就背叛了我
from the first.
请原谅我
Forgive me.
我从没想过...
I never meant--
求求您  卡丽熙  原谅我吧
please, Khaleesi, forgive me.
你把我的秘密出卖给杀死我父亲
You sold my secrets to the man who killed my father
-窃取我兄长王位的人...  -我保护您
- and stole my brother's throne... - I have protected you.
-我为您而战  为您杀戮  -还要我原谅
- Fought for you. Killed for you. - and you want me to forgive you?
我爱过您
I have loved you.
爱
Love?
爱  你竟敢说出这个字眼
Love? How can you say that to me?
要换了别人  我必定砍了他的脑袋
Any other man, and I would have you executed.
可是你  我不想在这座城里看到你
But you, I do not want you in my city
无论生死
dead or alive.
回你君临的主子那里
Go back to your masters in King's Landing.
拿出你的本事  求他们赦免吧
Collect your pardon if you can.
丹妮莉丝  求求您
Daenerys, please.
永远不要再试图碰我
Don't ever presume to touch me again
喊我的名字
or speak my name.
傍晚之前  收拾好东西
You have until dusk to collect your things
离开这座城市
and leave this city.
如果天亮后我发现你仍在弥林
If you're found in Meereen past break of day,
别怪我砍下你的人头扔进奴隶湾
I'll have your head thrown into Slaver's Bay.
走吧
Go.
快走
Now.
卡林湾是您的了  父亲大人
Moat Cailin is yours, Father.
跟我来
Walk with me.
洛克那儿有消息吗
Has there been any word from Locke?
没有
No.
无关紧要了
Unimportant.
一个瘸子  一个小屁孩
A cripple, a young boy.
北境的领主们都没见到他们
None of the northern lords have seen them.
八成是死了
Dead most likely.
很多铁种已经逃离北境
Most of the ironborn have fled the North.
而多亏你  又有很多铁种要跑了
Now more will follow, thanks to you.
告诉我你看到了什么
Tell me what you see.
荒野  田地  山丘
Moors, fields, hills.
告诉我你看到了什么
Tell me what you see.
什么也没有
Nothing.
这不是什么也没有
Not nothing.
而是整个北境
The North.
你往这个方向骑上七百哩  仍在北境之中
Ride 700 miles that way, you're still in the North.
这边可以骑四百哩
400 miles that way.
那边三百哩
300 miles that way.
北境的领土比其余六国的总和还要大
The North is larger than the other six kingdoms combined.
而我现在是北境守护
And I am the Warden of the North.
北境是我的了
The North is mine.
告诉我  你叫什么
Now tell me, what is your name?
拉姆斯·雪诺
Ramsay Snow.
不对  不是拉姆斯·雪诺
No, not Ramsay Snow.
打开看
Open it.
从今日起  直至你死去
From this day until your last day,
你是拉姆斯·波顿
you are Ramsay Bolton,
北境守护卢斯·波顿之子
son of Roose Bolton, Warden of the North.
您赐予我荣耀
You honor me.
我誓将不负您的英名
I swear I will uphold your name
继承您的传统
and your tradition.
我决不令您失望  父亲大人
I will be worthy of you, Father,
我郑重发誓
I promise.
快点  臭佬  我要洗澡了
Come, Reek, I'll be needing a bath.
请进
Yes?
我第一次见你时  你还是个孩子
First time I saw you, you were just a child.
一个刚从北境来到都城的小姑娘
A girl from the North come to the capital for the first time.
而现在已经长大了
Not a child any longer.
你为什么要帮我
Why did you help me?
要是他们发现你有罪
They would have thrown you through the Moon Door
就会把你扔出月门
if they found you guilty.
只怕不是因为这个吧
That's not an answer.
他们如果处决了你
If they'd have executed you,
接下来会怎么对待我呢
what would they have done with me?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也是
Neither do I.
与其押宝给陌生人
Better to gamble on the man you know
还不如在熟人身上赌一把
than the strangers you don't?
你自认为了解我吗
And you think you know me?
我知道你想要什么
I know what you want.
是吗
Do you?
我以为我会因此而开心
I thought it'd make me happy,
但没有  我不觉得开心
but it doesn't. Not really.
没什么能让你开心了
Nothing makes you happy.
-有很多事让我开心  -比如说
- Lots of things make me happy. - Like what?
杀波利佛和罗尔杰
Killing Polliver, killing Rorge.
所以你难过的是没有亲手杀了乔佛里
So you're sad because you didn't get to kill Joffrey yourself.
是这样吗
Is that it?
至少我想要亲眼看着他死
At least I could have been there to watch.
我想看到他那绝望的眼神
I wanted to see the look in his eyes when he knew it was over.
可不  那种眼神最让人舒坦了
Aye, nothing in the world beats that look.
他大半辈子都是你在保护
You protected him for most of his life.
你觉得你当时救得了他吗
You think you could have saved him?
我又不是替他尝酒的
I wasn't the damn wine taster.
那小混蛋是该死  但下毒...
Little shit deserved to die, but poison--
下毒是女人的伎俩
poison's a woman's weapon.
男人拿刀剑取命
Men kill with steel.
那是你自以为是的蠢话
That's your stupid pride talking.
所以这辈子你都当不了伟大的杀手
It's why you'll never be a great killer.
逼不得已我可以拿鸡骨头杀了乔佛里
I'd have killed Joffrey with a chicken bone if I had to.
我愿意花大价钱到场观赏
I'd pay good money to see that.
你应该让我帮你烧一下
You should have let me burn it.
区区小伤
It's a fleabite.
区区小伤已经大大拖慢了你的步伐
That fleabite's got you walking a lot slower than you used to.
还好前面没多远了
Well, we won't have to walk too much further.
你真觉得我姨妈会赎我吗
You really think my aunt will pay for me?
是  她肯定会
Aye, she'll pay.
我从来没见过她
I've never even met her.
不要紧  你是她的血亲
Doesn't matter. You're her blood.
还有家族  荣耀  尽是些狗屁道理
Family, honor, all that horseshit.
你们那帮王公贵族整天谈论这些东西
It's all you lords and ladies ever talk about.
我不是王公贵族
I'm not a lady.
欲过血门者何人
Who would pass the Bloody Gate?
血淋淋的猎狗  桑铎·克里冈
The bloody Hound, Sandor Clegane.
还有他的...
And his...
旅伴艾莉亚·史塔克
traveling companion Arya Stark,
莱莎·艾林夫人的外甥女
niece of your lady Lysa Arryn.
本人深表哀悼
Then I offer my condolences.
艾林夫人已死
Lady Arryn died.
就在三天前
Three days ago.
我从未出过家门  培提尔叔叔
I've never left home before, Uncle Petyr.
-我不敢离开  -你不必害怕
- I'm afraid to leave. - You shouldn't be.
母亲说  谷地主君属于鹰巢城
The Lord of the Vale belongs in the Eyrie, Mother said.
她说外面不安全
She said it's not safe outside.
家里对她而言也不安全
It wasn't safe for her inside.
人们有的命丧餐桌
People die at their dinner tables.
有的命丧床榻
They die in their beds.
有的蹲在夜壶上就没了命
They die squatting over their chamber pots.
每个人早晚都会死
Everybody dies sooner or later.
不要担忧死亡
Don't worry about your death.
操心你的生活罢
Worry about your life.
活着的每一天
Take charge of your life
都要好好把握
for as long as it lasts.
这才是身为谷地主君的意义所在
That is what it means to be Lord of the Vale.
可以出发了吗
Shall we go?
酒永远是最管用的
Wine always helps.
有劳了
I thank you for it.
比武审判
Trial by combat.
在诸神的见证下
Deciding a man's guilt or innocence
让两个人互相残杀
in the eyes of the gods
来判定另一个人是否有罪
by having two other men hack each other to pieces.
这就是诸神的真面目
Tells you something about the gods.
还有多久
How much longer?
快了
Soon.
你觉得奥柏伦会赢吗
Do you think Oberyn has a chance?
多恩的红毒蛇
The Red Viper of Dorne.
要是不厉害  谁给他取这个名号  是吧
You don't get a name like that unless you're deadly, right?
我没见识过他的身手
I've never seen him fight.
天哪  他要没命了  我也要没命了
Oh, he's going to die. I'm going to die.
奥柏伦很有自信
Oberyn believes in himself.
说得轻巧罢了
That's putting it mildly.
弑君罪会处以何种刑罚
What's the punishment for regicide?
五马分尸  绞刑
Drawing and quartering? Hanging?
-碾刑  -砍头
- Breaking at the wheel? - Beheading.
太平常了吧
Seems rather ordinary.
他还是我的外甥  那算什么呢
And he was my nephew as well, so what is that?
杀兄弟是弑兄
Fratricide is brothers.
杀儿子是弑子
Filicide is sons.
弑外甥  就它了
Nepoticide. That's the one.
弑母  弑父
Matricide, patricide,
杀婴  自杀
infanticide, suicide.
杀什么都有专门的叫法
There's no kind of killing that doesn't have its own word.
杀表亲没有
Cousins.
表亲  对啊
Cousins, you're right.
没有专门说杀表亲的词儿
There is no word for cousin killing.
漂亮
Well done.
你还记得我们的表亲欧森·兰尼斯特吗
Do you remember cousin Orson? Orson Lannister?
当然  奶妈不小心把他的脑袋撞在地上
Of course. Wet-nurse dropped him on his head.
-他成了傻子  -傻子
- Left him simple. - Simple?
成天坐在花园里
Used to sit all day in the garden.
拿石头砸甲虫
Crushing beetles with a rock.
这种事最让他开心了
Nothing made him happier.
这种事最让你开心了
Nothing made you happier.
你是不是觉得自己出身悲惨
You'd think being tormented from birth
所以跟这倒霉家伙有点同病相怜
would have given you some affinity for the afflicted.
恰恰相反  只有取笑他人的不幸
On the contrary. Laughing at another person's misery
我才觉得我和大家没有区别
was the only thing that made me feel like everyone else.
后来就没意思了
The joke wore thin, though.
对你是的  你逐渐疏远了
For you. You drifted away.
我有了别的兴趣
I had other interests.
是啊  别的兴趣
Yes, other interests.
但我还守着欧森
But I stayed with Orson.
为什么
Why?
我好奇啊
I was curious.
他为什么要砸甲虫呢
Why was he smashing all those beetles?
他从中得到什么呢
What did he get out of it?
我刚开始跑去问他
First thing I did was ask him.
"欧森  你为什么要砸甲虫"
"Orson, why are you smashing all those beetles?"
他给了我一个答案  "砸甲虫
He gave me an answer. "Smash the beetles.
砸死它们"
Smash 'em."
我没有就此作罢
I wasn't deterred.
我可是脑子最灵光的
I was the smartest person I knew.
不就是藏在一个傻子心里面的谜团吗
Certainly I had the wherewithal to unravel the mysteries
我肯定有办法解开
that lay at the heart of a moron.
于是我来到沃拉里克学士的藏书室
So I went to Maester Volarik's library.
沃拉里克  有一回他想摸我
Volarik. Tried to touch me once.
结果发现  长篇累牍的都是讲大人物
Turns out, far too much has been written about great men
根本不提傻子的事情
and not nearly enough about morons.
这不应该啊
Doesn't seem right.
总之  我没发现是什么
In any case, I found nothing
激发了欧森虐杀的本性
that illuminated the nature of Orson's affliction
他无情屠戮甲虫背后的情由
or the reason behind his relentless beetle slaughter.
于是我回来找凶手本人
So I went back to the source.
虽然我没法直接问欧森
I may not have been able to speak with Orson,
但我可以观察他  盯着他
but I could observe him, watch him
就像我们观察动物
the way men watch animals
为的是深入地理解它们的行为
to come to a deeper understanding of their behavior.
我观察他的同时
And as I watched,
越来越笃信一点
I became more and more sure of it.
那儿肯定出了什么状况
There was something happening there.
他的脸就像一本摊开的书
His face was like the page of a book
可惜我不懂书里所用的语言
written in a language I didn't understand.
他不是没头脑  他自有道理
But he wasn't mindless. He had his reasons.
我着了魔似的想搞清楚是什么道理
And I became possessed with knowing what they were.
于是花了大量的时间观察他
I began to spend inordinate amounts of time watching him.
我在花园里吃午饭
I would eat my lunch in the garden,
就着"喀喀喀"的节奏嚼羊肉
chewing my mutton to the music of..."Kuuh"
不观察他的时候  我满脑子都在想他
And when I wasn't watching him, I was thinking about him.
父亲执迷于家族的传承
Father droned on about the family legacy
我则沉浸于欧森的甲虫
and I thought about Orson's beetles.
我阅读坦格利安的征服史
I read the histories of Targaryen conquests.
我听见巨龙振翅的声音了吗  没有
Did I hear dragon wings? No.
我只听见"喀喀喀"
I heard..."Kuuh"
我还是搞不懂他为什么做这种事
And I still couldn't figure out why he was doing it.
可我必须知道  因为这太可怕了
And I had to know, because it was horrible
那么多甲虫不能无缘无故地死掉
that all these beetles should be dying for no reason.
每一天  这世上都有
Every day around the world,
很多男女老少死于非命
men, women, and children are murdered by the score.
谁管那群甲虫是为什么死的
Who gives a dusty fuck about a bunch of beetles?
我知道  我知道  可我就是害怕
I know, I know. But still, it filled me with dread.
一群又一群甲虫  一年又一年过去
Piles and piles of them, years and years of them.
多少爬地而行的小小生灵
How many countless living crawling things
粉身碎骨  化为齑粉  重归泥土
smashed and dried out and returned to the dirt?
我梦见自己
In my dreams I found myself
站在甲虫壳堆成的海滩上
standing on a beach made of beetle husks
放眼望去  无边无垠
stretching as far as the eye could see.
我哭着醒来
I woke up crying,
为它们碎裂的身体流泪
weeping for their shattered little bodies.
我有一次企图阻止欧森
I tried to stop Orson once.
他的块头抵你两个
He was twice your size.
他只是"喀"的一声把我推开
He just pushed me aside with a "Kuuh"
然后接着砸
and kept on smashing.
天天砸  直到那一天
Every day until that mule
骡子踢中了他的胸膛  他一命呜呼
kicked him in the chest and killed him.
你怎么看
So what do you think?
他为什么那样做
Why did he do it?
到底是怎么回事
What was it all about?
我不知道
I don't know.
祝你今天好运
Good luck today.
您的盔甲太轻薄了吧
Looks like very light armor.
我喜欢动作灵便
I like to move around.
至少戴顶头盔
You could at least wear a helmet.
战斗前不该喝酒
You shouldn't drink before a fight.
这是你长年累月混斗技场学到的经验吗
You learn this during your years in the fighting pits?
我战前必饮酒
I always drink before a fight.
这会害你送命的  然后连累我送命
It could get you killed. It could get me killed.
今日不是我的死期
Today is not the day I die.
你要和他打
You're going to fight that?
我要宰了他
I'm going to kill that.
他是我见过最高大的人
He is the biggest man I've ever seen.
等你躺在地上  块头就不妨事了
Size does not matter when you are flat on your back.
感谢诸神
Thank the gods.
在众神和诸位的见证下
In the sight of gods and men,
我们齐聚于此
we gather to ascertain
见证这个...提利昂·兰尼斯特
the guilt or innocence of this...
有罪抑或清白
man Tyrion Lannister.
愿圣母慈悲为怀
May the Mother grant them mercy.
愿天父主持公义
May the Father give them such justice as they deserve.
愿战士引导两位
And may the Warrior guide the hand...
代理骑士之手...
of our champion--
别丢下我一个人
Don't leave me alone in this world.
绝不会
Never.
他们告诉你我是谁了吗
Have they told you who I am?
一个死人
Some dead man.
我是伊莉亚·马泰尔的弟弟
I am the brother of Elia Martell.
你知道我为何大老远地跑来这座
Do you know why I have come all the way to this stinking
臭烘烘的城市
shit-pile of a city?
因为你
For you.
我来听你临死前的忏悔
I'm going to hear you confess before you die.
你奸了我姐姐
You raped my sister.
你杀了她
You murdered her.
你害了她孩子
You killed her children.
现在就说  我们便快一点完事
Say it now and we can make this quick.
说出来
Say it.
你奸了她
You raped her.
你杀了她
You murdered her.
你害了她孩子
You killed her children.
你奸了她
You raped her!
你杀了她
You murdered her!
你害了她孩子
You killed her children!
你奸了她
You raped her!
你杀了她
You murdered her!
你害了她孩子
You killed her children!
等等  你要死了吗
Wait. Are you dying?
不不不
No, no, no.
现在不准死  你还没有忏悔
You can't die yet. You haven't confessed.
说出来
Say it.
说出她的名字  伊莉亚·马泰尔
Say her name. Elia Martell.
你奸了她  你害了她孩子
You raped her. You killed her children.
伊莉亚·马泰尔
Elia Martell.
谁下的命令
Who gave you the order?
Who gave you the order?!
说出她的名字
Say her name!
你奸了她  你杀了她
You raped her! You murdered her!
你害了她孩子
You killed her children.
说出来  说出她的名字
Say it. Say her name.
说出来
Say it!
伊莉亚·马泰尔
Elia Martell.
我杀了她的小兔崽子
I killed her children.
接着我操了她
Then I raped her.
再下来我打碎了她的头颅  就像这样
Then I smashed her head in like this!
诸神旨意已明
The gods have made their will known.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
Tyrion Lannister,
以拜拉席恩家族的
in the name of King Tommen of the House Baratheon,
托曼一世之名
First of His Name,
我宣判你死刑
you are hereby sentenced to death.